Guide to the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Miscellaneous Scrapbook collection 1883-1967
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Miscellaneous Scrapbook collection
1883-1967
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0065scrapbook
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
10.8 linear feet
This is a collection includes assorted scrapbooks relating to the Pacific Northwest, Whatcom county, Bellingham, Lynden as well as information relating to local families and individuals. This collection also consists of twelve photo scrapbooks. Four of the scrapbooks contain photographs of fishing and canning industries in Alaska and the Puget Sound region. Three books contain scenes of WWI & WWII boats and shipbuilding. The remaining books contain images of home & family life.
The Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Miscellaneous Scrapbook collection is organized in accordance with the following series and subseries arrangement:
Series I: Photograph Scrapbooks, 1899-1954
Sub-series 1. Families and Individuals, 1900-1949
Sub-series 2. Pacific American Fisheries, 1899-1940
Sub-series 3. Shipbuilding and Commemoration in Bellingham, 1940s-1954
Series II: Non-Photograph Scrapbooks, 1862-1967
Sub-series 1. Pacific Northwest and Washington State, 1895-1963
Sub-series 2. Whatcom County, 1862-1967
The collection is open to the public.
The scrapbooks in the collection were a gift from the Whatcom County Museum in 1987. They originate from numerous sources. Known donors include Jack D. Mullin, Mrs. Albin C. Johnson, Linda Countryman, Mrs. Roland Richards, Gretchen H. Guerton, Bennett Sandberg, Mary Hickey, Mr. and Mrs. H.R. Frazier, and Mrs. George Siemons.
Additional records pertaining to the Bellingham Woman's Music Club can be found in the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies' Bellingham Woman's Music Club Records.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Higginson, Ella--1862-1940.; Judson, Phoebe Goodell, 1832-1926.; Newman, Thomas G. (Thomas George).
Eldridge family.; Roeder family.; Morse family.
Morse Hardware Company.; Pacific American Fisheries, Inc.; Beck's Theatre.
Northwest, Pacific--History--19th century--Sources.; Northwest, Pacific--History--20th century--Sources.; Northwest, Pacific--Description and travel--History--Sources.; Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Bellingham (Wash.)--Social life and customs--History--Sources.; Lynden (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Lynden (Wash.)--Social life and customs--History--Sources.
Scrapbooks--Washington (State).; Scrapbooks--Alaska.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.).; Tourism--Northwest, Pacific--History--Sources.; Passenger Ships--Northwest, Pacific--History--Sources--Photographs.; Fisheries--Alaska--History--Sources--Photographs.; Fisheries--Washington (State)--History--Sources--Photographs.; Salmon canning industry--Alaska--History--Sources--Photographs.; Salmon canning industry--Washington (State)--History--Sources -- Photographs.; Battleships--History--Sources--Photographs.; World War, 1914-1918--History--Sources--Photographs.; Indians of North America--Washington (State)--History--Sources--Photographs.; Poetry--20th century--Clippings.; Friendly societies--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Concert programs--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Playbills--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Theaters--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Performing arts--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Historic sites--Washington (State)--History--Sources.; Local government--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Pioneers--Washington (State)--Whatcom County--History--Sources.; Frontier and pioneer life--Washington (State)--Whatcom County--History--Sources.; Community life--Washington (State)--History--Sources.; Amuzements--Washington (State)--History--Sources.; Hardware stores--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Poets laureate--Washington (State)--History--Sources.; Politicians--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Bus lines--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Shipbuilding industry--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.; Women--Soceities and clubs--Bellingham (Wash.)--History--Sources.
Fishing and Canning; Alaska; Bellingham; Scrapbooks; Photographs; Ships and Shipping; City and Town Life
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Photograph Scrapbooks, 1899-1954; Series I
  - Families and Individuals, 1900-1949; Sub-series 1
    - Family photos and WWI battleships, 1900-1920 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Ships, trains, views in Whatcom County, 1901 and undated (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Vacations scenes of Seattle, Tacoma, Shelton, McNeil Penitentiary, and Port Townsend., 1903 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Views of Mt. Baker, circa 1920s (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Views of the Pacific Northwest including Oregon, Alaska, Washington, and Idaho, circa 1917-1939 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Family photos, 1920-1949 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Family photos, circa 1926 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Views in Whatcom County, Buildings in Bellingham, undated (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Pacific American Fisheries, 1899-1940; Sub-series 2
    - Pacific American Fisheries facilities and ships in Puget Sound area, Native Americans, 1899 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Views of Puget Sound and Alaskan Pacific American Fisheries facilities, 1916-1922 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Views of Alitak and other Pacific American Fisheries facilities in Alaska, 1940; undated (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Shipbuilding and Commemoration in Bellingham, 1940s-1954; Sub-series 3
    - Shipbuilding during WWII, circa 1940s (Box-folder 3/2)
    - WWII ships and shipbuilding in Bellingham, 1954 (Box-folder 3/3)
- Non-Photograph Scrapbooks, 1862-1967; Series II
  - Pacific Northwest and Washington State, 1895-1963; Sub-series 1
    - Washington Newspaper Clippings, Floral Cards, and Poems, 1895-1900; undated (Oversized 1/1)
    - Washington Newspaper Clippings regarding tax and financial matters, 1906-1907 (Oversized 1/2)
    - Loose pages from unknown scrapbook of historical sites in Washington, 1939 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Newspapers Clippings of Northwest Lore and History, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Newspapers Clippings of Northwest Lore and History, 1961-1967 (Oversized 2/2)
    - Washington Newspaper Clippings of John F. Kennedy Assassination, 1963 (Oversized 3/1)
  - Whatcom County, 1862-1967; Sub-series 2
    - Whatcom County General, 1883-1967
      - Newspaper Clippings about Bellingham, Ramona Park, and Lake Whatcom, 1883-1947 (Box-folder 4/2)
      - Newspaper Clippings of Poems and Lyrics, 1902-1907; undated (Box-folder 4/3)
      - Newspaper Clippings concerning local politics and receipts from fraternal organizations and newspaper subscriptions of S.E. Mullins', 1905-1912 (Oversized 3/1)
      - Newspaper Clippings of Poems and Lyrics, Floral Cards, 1906-1928 (Box-folder 4/4)
      - Rogues' Gallery of Whatcom County Pioneers Vol. I (newspaper clippings form Bellingham), 1921-1925 (Oversized 4/1)
      - Rogues' Gallery of Whatcom County Pioneers Vol. II (newspaper clippings form Bellingham), 1926-1952 (Oversized 4/2)
      - Whatcom County Chapter of Daughters of American Revolution, 1933-1962 (Oversized 5/1)
      - Bellingham and Whatcom County Book VI (newspaper articles), 1957-1959 (Oversized 5/2)
      - Bellingham and Whatcom County Book VII (newspaper articles), 1959-1967 (Oversized 5/3)
    - Bellingham, Washington, 1890-1958
      - Newspaper Clippings and Poetry (Unknown Author), 1862-1914 (Oversized 4/5)
      - Newspaper Clippings and other assorted clippings, 1890-1896; 1940 (Box-folder 5/1)
      - T.G. Newman’s (Attorney) Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings, 1895-1945 (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Beck's Theater Scrapbook, 1890's-Early 1900's (Oversized 6/1)
      - Mrs. Alan R. Jenkins' Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings written by, or about, Ella Higginson, 1900-1947 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - Bellingham Newspaper Clippings of area's early history, early 1900's (Oversized 6/2)
      - Frank G. Kelly's scrapbook of WWI pictures, 1916-1921 (Oversized 6/3)
      - Eldridge Family (Primarily), 1916-1938 (Oversized 7/1)
      - Helen Siemons Scrapbook, 1932-1958 (Box-folder 6/1)
      - Programs and clippings from performances of Bellingham State Normal School and Bellingham Woman's Music Club (additional related materials are in the Bellingham Woman's Music Club Records), 1933-1944 (Oversized 7/2)
      - Ted and Elsie Larson Scrapbook of cards and newspaper clippings, 1930s-1960s (Oversized 8/1)
      - Newspaper Clippings on proposed boat haven for Purse Seine Fleet, 1936 (Box-folder 6/2)
      - Bellingham High School Symphonic Band, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 6/3)
      - Don E. Satterlee (Mayor of Bellingham), 1947-1949 (Oversized 6/4)
      - Scrapbook about the "Vigilant," a Five Mast Schooner (was created initially as a float for the Blossom Festival), 1947-1958 (Oversized 8/2)
      - Bellingham Bus System Newspaper Clippings Scrapbook, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Lynden, Washington, 1923-1960s
      - Newspaper Clippings Scrapbook of Lynden History, 1923-1960s (Oversized 9/1)